A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Economic Opportunity and Assets Program, Vice President, Office Files of Pablo Farias FA1358
Rockefeller Archive Center
- General files, 1954-2014; 4; 4.56 Cubic Feet 12 letter size boxes
  - Visit to Jakarta, Indonesia Office, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 143)
  - Visit to Lagos, Nigeria Office, February 2007 - Pablo Farias, Jacob Gayle, and Frank DeGiovanni (Box 14, Folder 144)
  - Ford Foundation Sexuality Reproductive Health Learning Group Meeting, March 2007, New Orleans, Louisiana, 2000-2007 (Box 14, Folder 145-146)
  - Knowledge transfer exit interview guidance, undated (Box 14, Folder 147)
  - Old Ford Foundation publications - Current Interests of the Ford Foundation and Letter issues, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 148)
  - Ford Foundation grantmakers' orientation handbooks, 1999-2013 (Box 15, Folder 149-151)
  - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS) 2006 Reflection Memos (Box 15, Folder 152)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program (KCF) September 2006 New York Staff Retreat - El Museo del Barrio and Teatro Hecksher (Box 15, Folder 153)
  - Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS) Global Meeting, November 2006, New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 15, Folder 154)
  - Ford Foundation Trustee Site Visit, April 2007, Gulf Coast Region (Box 16, Folder 155)
  - Jacob Gayle - Ford Foundation Global Initiative on HIV/AIDS, 2005-2010 (Box 16, Folder 156-157)
  - Ford Foundation Global Initiative on HIV/AIDS, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 158)
  - Peace and Social Justice (PSJ) discussions about workload reduction, 1997 August 1 (Box 16, Folder 159)
  - Peace and Social Justice (PSJ) Incentive Fund, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 160)
  - Gender and Institutional Change Project, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 161)
  - Special Initiative for Africa (SIA), undated (Box 16, Folder 162)
  - Report on Civil Rights and the Asian American Community, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 163)
  - Mapping Asia's Human Rights Organizations, undated (Box 16, Folder 164)
  - Governance and Civil Society (GCS) Portfolio on Democratic Accountability and Social and Economic Policy (Summary of Grants - The First Two Years), 1997 (Box 16, Folder 165)
  - Pictures from visits to China and India, 2005-2007 (Box 17, Folder 166)
    File contains pictures of Ford Foundation staff visits to China in 2005 and India in 2007 through arrangement by the Foundation's Beijing and New Delhi Offices respectively. Many of these pictures are computer prints on paper while some have been put on cardstock.
  - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC) - Israel Program Consultation, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 167)
  - Ford Foundation Trustees Discussion on Affirmative Action California Ballot Initiative 209, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 168)
  - Research on the termination of affirmative action at the University of California, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 169)
  - Terrorism and international security - Gary Sick and Brian Urquhart, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 170)
  - Towards a System of Youth Development: Replacing Work, Service, and Learning Deficits with Opportunities - Gordon Berlin statement to United States Congress, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 171)
  - Grant-Talk, 1999-2013 (Box 17, Folder 172)
  - Rural United States agenda, 2007-2008 (Box 17, Folder 173)
  - Indian Ocean 2005 Tsunami response (Box 17, Folder 174)
  - Ford Foundation Program Directors memo - Reflections on Foundation's Programming, 2000 November 15 (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - Review of Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS) biennial program plans and budgets and work on human sexuality, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 176)
  - Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ) Vice President Bradford Smith memos and other documents, 1996-2000 (Box 17, Folder 177)
  - Materials Related to the Foundation Policy on External Diversity, 1986-1996 (Box 17, Folder 178)
  - Innovations in American Government Awards Program - 1997 Awards (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Ford Foundation Program Division November 2007 Briefing Book (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - Ford Foundation Fund for Community Organizing, 2001-2003 (Box 18, Folder 181)
  - Ford Foundation Assets programs Trustee Committee 2008-2010 meetings, 2005-2013 (Box 18, Folder 182-183)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program (KCF) overview, 1996-2006 (Box 18, Folder 184-186)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Initiative Strategy Overview, 2011 May (Box 19, Folder 187)
  - Visionary Leadership Grants for Ford Foundation 75th Anniversary, 2008-2011 (Box 19, Folder 188)
  - Ford Foundation June 21, 2013 convening - National Briefing on Native Hawaiians and Economic Needs of Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders (Box 19, Folder 189)
  - Hattaway Communications - Economic Opportunity and Assets (EOA) message, 2010-2012 (Box 19, Folder 190)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) - Theory of Change, 2010-2012 (Box 19, Folder 191)
  - Rio Plus20 Conference, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil - Planning, 2011-2012 (Box 19, Folder 192)
  - Ford Foundation 75th Anniversary Forum The Just City - Planning, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 193)
  - Ford Foundation Learning Team - Organizational learning, 2013-2014 (Box 19, Folder 194)
    Restricted – Open in 2025
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) September 13, 2011 Retreat - Communication Strategies and Approaches (Box 19, Folder 195)
  - Initiative Evaluation and Impact Reporting and Results Reporting Working Group (RRWG), 2011-2013 (Box 20, Folder 196-197)
  - Results Reporting Working Group (RRWG) - Initiative Results Reports, 2012-2013 (Box 20, Folder 198-199)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Evaluation and Impact Assessment, 2009-2011 (Box 20, Folder 200)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Metropolitan Opportunity unit Impact Assessment and Theory of Change, 2011 (Box 20, Folder 201)
  - Impact Assessment of Strategy, 2006-2010 (Box 20, Folder 202)
  - Impact Assessment of Strategy - Harvard University Business School, Leading and Governing High Performing Nonprofit Organizations (LGN), 2009-2011 (Box 20, Folder 203)
  - 100,000 Strong Foundation, 2011-2013 (Box 21, Folder 204)
  - Initiative Lines of Work Summaries, 2008-2009 (Box 21, Folder 205)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Initiative Strategy Overview draft - Lindsey Steinmetz, 2011 March (Box 21, Folder 206)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) September 13, 2011 Team Retreat (Box 21, Folder 207)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) October 16, 2012 Global Staff Meeting (Box 21, Folder 208)
  - Ford Foundation 2012 Initiative Results Report, 2012 December (Box 21, Folder 209)
  - Ford Foundation 2012 Initiative Results Reports and Initiative Status Reports, 2012-2013 (Box 21, Folder 210-211)
  - Ford Foundation Worldwide Meeting November 2014, New York City, New York, 2012-2014 (Box 22, Folder 212)
- Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Unit files, 2005-2013; 5; .76 Cubic Feet 2 letter size boxes
  This series contains files specifically concerning the work of the Ford Foundation's Economic Opportunity and Assets Program's (EOA) units. Pablo Farias whose office maintained these files served as Vice President of EOA. The units documented in the series are Quality Employment, Natural Resources and Sustainable Development, Financial Assets, and Metropolitan Opportunity. Helen Neuborne served as Director of Quality Employment, David Kaimowitz served as Director of Natural Resources and Sustainable Development, Frank DeGiovanni served as Director of Financial Assets, and George McCarthy served as Director of Metropolitan Opportunity.
  Materials in the series document the different program interests of the EOA units. Quality Employment focused on workers' conditions and benefits, Natural Resources and Sustainable Development focused on economic development compatible with environment and climate change concerns, Financial Assets focused on building financial security, and Metropolitan Opportunity focused on economic development for urban communities.
  The files document the units' interests through the records they hold pertaining to specific meetings (both internal unit meetings and unit organized and supported topic meetings) and projects.
  There are other Ford Foundation collections containing files pertaining to the EOA unit activities.
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Quality Employment unit (Helen Neuborne, Director), 2008-2011 (Box 23, Folder 220-222)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Quality Employment unit (Helen Neuborne, Director) - February 19, 2010 meeting with United States Secretary of Labor Hilda Solis (Box 23, Folder 223)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Natural Resources and Sustainable Development unit (David Kaimowitz, Director) - Foundation CEO Meeting on Climate, March 8, 2010, Washington D.C. (Box 23, Folder 224)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Natural Resources and Sustainable Development unit (David Kaimowitz, Director) - February 2010 Unit Meeting, 2009-2010 (Box 23, Folder 225)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Natural Resources and Sustainable Development unit (David Kaimowitz, Director), 2009-2010 (Box 23, Folder 226)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Financial Assets unit (Frank DeGiovanni, Director) - February 17, 2010 Ford Foundation Social Security Summit, 2009-2010 (Box 23, Folder 227)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Financial Assets unit (Frank DeGiovanni, Director) - Savings and Conditional Cash Transfers (CCTs): A Global Colloquium, 2010 (Box 23, Folder 228)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Financial Assets unit (Frank DeGiovanni, Director), 2012 (Box 24, Folder 229)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Financial Assets unit (Frank DeGiovanni, Director) - Social Security grants, 2005 (Box 24, Folder 230)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Financial Assets unit (Frank DeGiovanni, Director), 2010 (Box 24, Folder 231)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Financial Assets unit (Frank DeGiovanni, Director) - Wealth Creation and Rural-Urban Linkages, Wayne Fawbush, 2008-2009 (Box 24, Folder 232)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Metropolitan Opportunity unit (George McCarthy, Director), 2009-2011 (Box 24, Folder 233-234)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Metropolitan Opportunity unit (George McCarthy, Director) - Auto Communities and the Next Economy, May 18, 2010, Washington D.C. (Box 24, Folder 235)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Metropolitan Opportunity unit (George McCarthy, Director) - November 2009 site visit to Detroit, Michigan (Box 24, Folder 236)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Metropolitan Opportunity unit (George McCarthy, Director) - Ford Foundation/Kresge Foundation meeting, 2010 (Box 24, Folder 237)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Metropolitan Opportunity unit (George McCarthy, Director) - Grantee Strategic Communications Convening, 2010 (Box 24, Folder 238)
  - Economic Opportunity and Assets Program (EOA) Metropolitan Opportunity unit (George McCarthy, Director) - Strategy statements, circa 2013 (Box 24, Folder 239)